<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/file-management/</link>
    <description>Chapter 3 RHCSA Notes - File Management 7 File types regular directory block special device character special device symbolic link named pipe socket Commands&#xA;ls stat file Regular files Text or binary data. Represented by hyphen (-). Directory Files Identified by the letter “d” in the beginning of ls output. Block and Character (raw) Special Device Files All hardware has device file in /dev/. Used by system to communicate with device. Identified by “c” or “b” in ls listing. Each device driver is assigned a unique number called the major number Character device Reads and writes 8 bits at a time. Serial Block device Receives data in fixed block size determined by drivers 512 or 4096 bytes Major Number Used by kernel to recognize device driver type. Column 5 of ls listing. ls -l /dev/sda Minor Number Each device controlled by the same device driver gets a Minor Number Applies to disk partitions as well. The same driver can control multiple devices of the same type. Column 6 of ls listing ls -l /dev/sda Symbolic Links Shortcut to another file or directory. Begins with “l” in ls listing. ls -l /usr/sbin/vigr lrwxrwxrwx. 1 root root 4 Jul 21 14:36 /usr/sbin/vigr -&gt; vipw Compression and Archiving Archiving Preserves file attributes such as ownership, owning group, and timestamp. Preserves extended file attributes such as ACLs and SELinux contexts. Syntax of tar and star are identical. star command tar (tape archive) command Create, append, update, list, and extract files/directory tree to/from a file called a tarball(tarfile) Can compress a tarball after it’s been created. Automatically removes “/” so you do not have to specify the full pathname when restoring files at any location. flags tar -c :: Create tarball. tar -f :: Specify tarball name. tar -p :: Preserve file permissions. Default for the root user. Specify this if you create an archive as a normal user. tar -r :: Append files to the end of an existing uncompressed tarball. tar -t :: List contents of a tarball. tar -u :: Append files to the end of an existing uncompressed tarball provided the specified files being added are newer. -z -j -C</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/file-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>