<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/linux/time-synchronization/</link>
    <description>Time Synchronization Network Time Protocol (NTP) Networking protocol for synchronizing the system clock with remote time servers for accuracy and reliability. Having steady and exact time on networked systems allows time-sensitive applications, such as authentication and email applications, backup and scheduling tools, financial and billing systems, logging and monitoring software, and file and storage sharing protocols, to function with precision. Sends a stream of messages to configured time servers and binds itself to the one with least amount of delay in its responses, the most accurate, and may or may not be the closest distance-wise. Client system maintains a drift in time in a file and references this file for gradual drop in inaccuracy. Chrony RHEL 9 implementation of NTP Uses the UDP port 123. If enabled, it starts at system boot and continuously operates to keep the system clock in sync with a more accurate source of time. Performs well on computers that are occasionally connected to the network, attached to busy networks, do not run all the time, or have variations in temperature. Time Sources A time source is any reference device that acts as a provider of time to other devices. The most precise sources of time are the atomic clocks. They use Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) for time accuracy. They produce radio signals that radio clocks use for time propagation to computer servers and other devices that require correctness in time. When choosing a time source for a network, preference should be given to the one that takes the least amount of time to respond. This server may or may not be closest physically. The common sources of time employed on computer networks are:</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/linux/time-synchronization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>