<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/linux/rhcsa/advanced-user-management-labs/</link>
    <description>Advanced User Management Labs Lab: Set and Confirm Password Aging with chage (root) Set password aging parameters for user100 to mindays (-m) 7, maxdays (-M) 28, and warndays (-W) 5: chage -m 7 -M 28 -W 5 user100 Confirm chage -l user100 Set the account expiry to January 31, 2020 chage -E 2020-01-31 user100 Verify the new account expiry setting chage -l user100 Lab: Set and Confirm Password Aging with passwd (root) Set password aging attributes for user200 to mindays 10, maxdays 90, and warndays 14: passwd -n 10 -x 90 -w 14 user200 Confirm: passwd -S user200 Set the number of inactivity days to 5: passwd -i 5 user200 Confirm: passwd -S user200 Ensure that the user is forced to change their password at next login: passwd -e user200 Confirm: passwd -S user200 Lab: Lock and Unlock a User Account with usermod and passwd (root) Obtain the current password information for user200 from the shadow file: grep user200 /etc/shadow Lock the account for user200: usermod -L user200 Confirm: grep user200 /etc/shadow Unlock the account with either of the following: usermod -U user200 or passwd -u user200 confirm grep user200 /etc/shadow Lab: Create a Group and Add Members (root) Create the group linuxadm with GID 5000: groupadd -g 5000 linuxadm Create a group called dba with the same GID as that of group linuxadm: groupadd -o -g 5000 dba Confirm: grep linuxadm /etc/group grep dba /etc/group Add user1 as a secondary member of group dba using the usermod command. The existing membership for the user must remain intact. usermod -aG dba user1 Verify the updated group membership information for user1 by extracting the relevant entry from the group file, and running the id and groups command for user1: grep dba /etc/group id user1 groups user1 Lab: Modify and Delete a Group Account (root) Alter the name of linuxadm to sysadm: groupmod -n sysadm linuxadm Change the GID of sysadm to 6000: groupmod -g 6000 sysadm Confirm: grep sysadm /etc/group grep linuxadm /etc/group Delete sysadm group and confirm: groupdel sysadm grep sysadm /etc/group Lab: To switch from user1 (assuming you are logged in as user1) into root without executing the startup scripts su switch to user100 su - user100 See what whoami and logname reports now: whoami logname use su as follows and execute this privileged command to obtain desired results: su -c &#39;firewall-cmd --list-services&#39; Lab: Add user1 to sudo file but only for the cat command. Open up /etc/sudoers and add the following: user1 ALL=/usr/bin/cat run cat as user1 with and without sudo: cat /etc/sudoers sudo cat /etc/sudoers Lab: Add user and command aliases to the sudoer file. Add the following to the bottom of the sudoers file: Cmnd_Alias PKGCMD = /usr/bin/yum, /usr/bin/rpm User_Alias PKGADM = user1, user100, user200 PKGADM ALL=PKGCMD Run rpm or yum with sudo as one of the users. sudo yum Lab: Take a look at examples in the sudoers file. cat /etc/sudoers Lab: Viewing owner and group information Create a file file1 as user1 in their home directory and exhibit the file’s long listing: touch file1 ls -l file1 View the corresponding UID and GID instead, you can specify the -n option with the command: ls -ln file1 Lab: Modify File Owner and Owning Group Change into the /tmp directory and create file10 and dir10: cd /tmp touch file10 mkdir dir10 Check and validate that both attributes are set to user1: ls -l file10 ls -ld dir10 Set the ownership of file10 to user100 and confirm: sudo chown user100 file10 ls -l file10 Alter the owning group to dba and verify: sudo chgrp dba file10 ls -l file10 Change the ownership to user200 and owning group to user100 and confirm: sudo chown user200:user100 file10 Modify the ownership to user200 and owning group to dba recursively on dir10 and validate: sudo chown -R user200:dba dir10 ls -ld dir10 Lab: Create User and Configure Password Aging (root) Create group lnxgrp with GID 6000. groupadd lnxgrp -g 6000 Create user user5000 with UID 5000 and GID 6000. Assign this user a password. useradd -u 5000 -g 6000 user5000 Establish password aging attributes so that this user cannot change their password within 4 days after setting it and with a password validity of 30 days. This user should start getting warning messages for changing password 10 days prior to account lock down. chage -m 4 -M 30 -W 10 user5000 This user account needs to expire on the 20th of December, 2021. chage -E 2021-12-20 user5000 Lab 6-2: Lock and Unlock User (root) Lock the user account for user5000 using the passwd command, and passwd -l user5000 confirm by examining the change in the /etc/shadow file. cat /etc/shadow Try to log in with user5000 and observe what happens. su - user1 su - user5000 Use the usermod command and unlock</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/linux/rhcsa/advanced-user-management-labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>