<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RHCSA :: Linux Reader</title>
    <link>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/</link>
    <description>RHCSA</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RHCSA Study Tracker</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/rhcsa-study-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/rhcsa-study-tracker/</guid>
      <description>Chapter Read/ Highlight Outline/labs Review/Labs 3 Review/Labs 4 Review/Labs Chapter Installation X X X X X 1 Interaction X X X X X 2 File Management X X X X X 3 Advanced File Management X X X X X 4 Basic User Management X X X X X 5 Advanced User Management X X X X 6 Bash X X X X 7 Process and Task Scheduling X X X X 8 Basic Package Management X X X X 9 Advanced Package Management X X X X 10 Boot Process, Grub2, and Kernel X X X X 11 System Initialization, Message Logging, and System Tuning X X X X 12 Storage Management X X X 13 Local File Systems and Swap X X X 14 Networking Network Devices and Network Connections X X X 15 Network File System (NFS) X X X 16 DNS and Time Synchronization X X X 17 The Secure Shell Service X X X 18 The Linux Firewall X X X 19 Security Enhanced Linux X X X 20 Shell Scripting X X X 21 Containers X X X 22 Sample Exam 1 X X X 23 Sample exam 2 X X X 24 Sample Exam 3 X X 25 Sample Exam 4 X X 26</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHCSA Vagrant Lab Setup</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/rhcsa-vagrant-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/rhcsa-vagrant-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>We are going to use Vagrant to set up two RHEL 8 servers with some custom configuration options. I will include some helpful Vagrant commands at the end if you get stuck.&#xA;In this guide, I will be using Fedora 38 as my main operating system. I use Fedora because it is similar in features to Red Hat Linux Distributions. This will give me even more practice for the RHCSA exam as I use it in day-to-day operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Need to Learn Man Pages</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/using-man-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/using-man-pages/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RzAkjX_9B7E&amp;t=295s&#xA;Man (manual) pages are the built in help system for Linux. They contain documentation for most commands.&#xA;Run the man command on a command to get to it’s man page. man man&#xA;Navigating a man page h&#xA;Get help q&#xA;Quit out of the man page Man uses less&#xA;^ mean ctrl&#xA;^f Forward one page&#xA;^b backward one page&#xA;can use # followed by command to repeat that many times</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>