<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/linux/rhcsa/rhcsa-notes/processes-and-priorities/</link>
    <description>Processes and Priorities Process&#xA;a unit for provisioning system resources. any program, application, or command that runs on the system. created in memory when a program, application, or command is initiated. organized in a hierarchical fashion. Each process has a parent process (a.k.a. a calling process) that spawns it. A single parent process may have one or many child processes passes many of its attributes to them at the time of their creation. Each process is assigned an exclusive identification number (Process IDentifier (PID)) is used by the kernel to manage and control the process through its lifecycle. When a process completes its lifespan or is terminated, this event is reported back to its parent process, and all the resources provisioned to it (cpu cycles, memory, etc.) are then freed and the PID is removed from the system. background system processes are called daemons which sit in the memory and wait for an event to trigger a request to use their services. /proc Where information for each running process is recorded and maintained. Referenced by ps and other commands Process States Five basic process states: running being executed by the system CPU. sleeping waiting for input from a user or another process. waiting has received the input it was waiting for and is now ready to run as soon as its turn comes. stopped currently halted and will not run even when its turn comes unless a signal is sent to change its behavior. zombie Dead. Exists in the process table alongside other process entries takes up no resources. entry is retained until its parent process permits it to die also called a defunct process.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/linux/rhcsa/rhcsa-notes/processes-and-priorities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>