<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/administration-tools/</link>
    <description>Administration Tools ip Display monitor and manage network interfaces, routing, connections, traffic, etc. ifup&#xA;Brings up an interface ifdown&#xA;Brings down an interface nmcli&#xA;Creates, updates, deletes, activates, and deactivates a connection profile. nmcli command Create, view, modify, remove, activate, and deactivate network connections. Control and report network device status. Supports abbreviation of commands. Operates on 7 different object categories.&#xA;general networking connection (c)(con) device (d)(dev) radio monitor agent [root@server200 system-connections]# nmcli --help Usage: nmcli [OPTIONS] OBJECT { COMMAND | help } OPTIONS -a, --ask ask for missing parameters -c, --colors auto|yes|no whether to use colors in output -e, --escape yes|no escape columns separators in values -f, --fields &lt;field,...&gt;|all|common specify fields to output -g, --get-values &lt;field,...&gt;|all|common shortcut for -m tabular -t -f -h, --help print this help -m, --mode tabular|multiline output mode -o, --overview overview mode -p, --pretty pretty output -s, --show-secrets allow displaying passwords -t, --terse terse output -v, --version show program version -w, --wait &lt;seconds&gt; set timeout waiting for finishing operations OBJECT g[eneral] NetworkManager\&#39;s general status and operations n[etworking] overall networking control r[adio] NetworkManager radio switches c[onnection] NetworkManager\&#39;s connections d[evice] devices managed by NetworkManager a[gent] NetworkManager secret agent or polkit agent m[onitor] monitor NetworkManager changes 3. connection Activates, deactivates, and administers network connections. Options:</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://linuxreader.com/linux/rhcsa/administration-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>