<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/networking/ccna/newccnanotes/8vlans/</link>
    <description>1.0 Network Fundamentals1.13 Describe switching concepts&#xA;1.13.a MAC learning and aging1.13.b Frame switching&#xA;1.13.c Frame flooding1.13.d MAC address table&#xA;2.0 Network Access2.1 Configure and verify VLANs (normal range) spanning multiple switches&#xA;2.1.a Access ports (data and voice)2.1.b Default VLAN2.1.c Connectivity&#xA;2.2 Configure and verify interswitch connectivity2.2.a Trunk ports&#xA;2.2.b 802.1Q2.2.c Native VLAN&#xA;Virtual LAN Concepts&#xA;reasons for choosing to create smaller broadcast domains (VLANs):&#xA;-reduce CPU overhead on each devicereduce security risks different security policies per VLAN more flexible designs that -group users by department, or by groups that work together, instead of by physical location solve problems more quickly-failure domain for many problems is the same set of devices as those in the same broadcast domain reduce the workload for the Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) -by limiting a VLAN to a single access switch&#xA;802.1q and ISL&#xA;802.1Q -inserts a 4-byte 802.1Q VLAN header into the Ethernet header&#xA;12 - bit VLAN ID field inside the 802.1Q header –supports a theoretical maximum of 212 (4096) VLANs, but in practice it supports a maximum of 4094. Both 802.1Q and ISL use 12 bits to tag the VLAN ID, withtwo reserved values [0 and 4095]. 802.1q header includes Type, priority, Flag, Vlan ID&#xA;normal–1 to 1005. all switches can use-range&#xA;Only some switches can use 1006 to 4094&#xA;depends on the configuration of the VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) Extended range Cisco switches break the range of VLAN IDs (1–4094) into the normal range and the extended range. 231852+ 802.1Q simply does not add an 802.1Q header to frames in the native VLAN&#xA;#show vlan brief&#xA;VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP)&#xA;vtp mode transparent vtp mode off -The server switches can configure VLANs in the standard range only (1The client switches cannot configure VLANs. –1005). Both servers and clients may be learning new VLANs from other switches and seeing their VLANs deleted by other switches because of VTP. If your switch usesVTP server or client mode show running - does not list any vlan commands - confi g show vtp status If possible to learn more about VTP for other purposes.in the lab, switch to disable VTP and ignore VTP for your switch configuration practice until you decide negotiate ISL or 802.1q If both switches support both protocols, they use ISL; -otherwise, they use the protocol that both support. Dynamic Trunking Protocol (DTP). switchport trunk encapsulation {dot1q | isl | negotiate} - configure the type or allow DTP to negotiate the type. Access-always access trunk-always trunk dynamic desirable--initiates negotiation messages and responds to negotiation messagesAccess if other side is access, otherwise trunk dynamic auto-passively waits to receive trunk negotiation messages VLAN Trunking Configuration</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/networking/ccna/newccnanotes/8vlans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>