<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/linux/rhcsa/job-scheduling/</link>
    <description>Job Scheduling Run a command at a specified time. One time or periodic. One time command can be used to run a command at a time with low system usage. Periodic examples: creating a compressed archive trimming log files monitoring the system running a custom script removing unwanted files from the system. atd and crond manage jobs atd Run one time jobs. atd daemon retries a missed job at the same time next day. Does not need a restart with changes crond Run periodic scheduled jobs. Daemon reads the schedules in files located in the /var/spool/cron and /etc/cron.d directories. scans these files in short intervals updates the in-memory schedules to reflect any modifications. runs a job at its scheduled time only does not entertain any missed jobs. Does not need a restart with changes Controlling user access all users can schedule jobs access to job scheduling can be edited must add users to allowed or deny file in /etc /etc/at.allow &amp; /etc/cron.allow Does not exist by default. /etc/at.deny &amp; /etc/cron.deny Exists by default list one username per line root user is always permitted Denial message appears if unauthorized user attempts to use at or cron. Only if there is an entry for the calling user in the deny files. at.allow / cron.allow at.deny / cron.deny Impact Exists, and contains user entries Existence does not matter All users listed in allow files are permitted Exists, but is empty Existence does not matter No users are permitted Does not exist Exists, and contains user entries All users, other than those listed in deny files, are permitted Does not exist Exists, but is empty All users are permitted Does not exist Does not exist No users are permitted Scheduler Log File /var/log/cron - Logs for both atd and cron Shows - time of activity - hostname - process name and PID - owner - message for each invocation - service start time and delays - must have root privileges to view</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/linux/rhcsa/job-scheduling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>