<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://perfectdarkmode.com/linux/rhcsa/firewalld-zones/</link>
    <description>firewalld Zones firewalld The host-based firewall solution employed in RHEL uses a kernel module called netfilter together with a filtering and packet classification framework called nftables for policing the traffic movement. It also supports other advanced features such as Network Address Translation (NAT) and port forwarding. This firewall solution inspects, modifies, drops, or routes incoming, outgoing, and forwarded network packets based on defined rulesets. Default host-based firewall management service in RHEL Ability to add, modify, or delete firewall rules immediately without disrupting current network connections or restarting the service process. Also allows to save rules persistently so that they are activated automatically at system reboots. Lets you perform management operations at the command line using the firewall-cmd command, graphically using the web console, or manually by editing rules files. Stores the default rules in files located in the /usr/lib/firewalld directory, and those that contain custom rules in the /etc/firewalld directory. The default rules files may be copied to the custom rules directory and modified. firewalld Zones Easier and transparent traffic management. Define policies based on the trust level of network connections and source IP addresses. A network connection can be part of only one zone at a time; A zone can have multiple network connections assigned to it. Zone configuration may include services, ports, and protocols that may be open or closed. May include rules for advanced configuration items such as masquerading, port forwarding, NAT’ing, ICMP filters, and rich language. Rules for each zone are defined and manipulated independent of other zones. Match source ip to zone that matches address &gt; match based on zone the interface is in &gt; matches default zone</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://perfectdarkmode.com/linux/rhcsa/firewalld-zones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>