<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://perfectdarkmode.com/networking/newccnanotes/7switchinterfaces/</link>
    <description>7switchinterfaces 1.0 Network Fundamentals1.1 Explain the role and function of network components 1.1.b L2 and L3 switches1.4 Describe switching concepts Configuring Speed, Duplex, and Description autonegotiate○○What speed to useenabled by default&#xA;duplex {auto | full | half} and speed {auto | 10 | 100 | 1000} ○configure the speed and duplex settings&#xA;(config - add a text description to the interface - int) # description text&#xA;show interfaces status - lists port #, Name, status, vlan, duplex, speed, and type&#xA;a-full and aa-means that the listed speed and duplex values were autonegotiated.- 100 IEEE autonegotiation (IEEE standard 802.3u) each node states what it can do, and then each node picks the best options that both nodes support: -the fastest speed and the best duplex setting, with full duplex being better than half duplex. disable autonegotiation-Configure both the speed and duplex on a switch interface when a node tries to use autonegotiation but hears nothing from the device.&#xA;Speed: Use your slowest supported speed (often 10 Mbps).Duplex: If your speed = 10 or 100, use half duplex; otherwise, use full duplex.&#xA;Cisco switches can actually sense the speed used by other nodes, even without IEEE autonegotiation. -Cisco switches use this slightly different logic to choose the speed when autonegotiation fails: Speed: Sense the speed (without using autonegotiation), but if that fails, use the IEEE default (slowest supported speed, often 10 Mbps). Duplex: Use the IEEE defaults: If speed = 10 or 100, use half duplex; otherwise, use full duplex. -Ethernet interfaces using speeds faster than 1 Gbps always use full duplex.hubs do not react to autonegotiation messages Autonegotiation show interfaces and show interfaces description -Line status = administratively downProtocol status = down Interface status = disabled Shutdown command is configured -Line status = downProtocol status = down Interface status = notconnect Cable, speed mismatch, neighbor device is off , shutdown, or err-disabled -Line status = upProtocol status = down Interface status = notconnect Not expected on LAN switch physical interfaces -Line status = downProtocol status = down (err-disabled) Interface status = err-disabled Port security has disabled the interface -Line status = upProtocol status = up Interface status = connected the interface is working show interfaces fa0/13 - -lists the speed and duplex for interface Fast Ethernet 0/13with nothing implying that the values were learned through autonegotiation.(without the status option) speed manually set 10 Mbps on one switch and 100 Mbps on the other Quick Commands Speed/ duplex #duplex auto/full/half#speed auto/10/100/1000 Description #description (text) Interface #show interfaces status#show interfaces fa0/3 7. Switch InterfacesWednesday, June 30, 2021 8:01 AM speed manually set 10 Mbps on one switch and 100 Mbps on the other-both switches would list the port in a down/down or notconnect state if the duplex settings do not match-the switch interface will still be in a connected (up/up) or connected state. How to identify duplex mismatch problems, --check the duplex setting on each end of the link to see if the values mismatch.watch for incrementing collision and late collision counters Common Layer 1 problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://perfectdarkmode.com/networking/newccnanotes/7switchinterfaces/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>