<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/linux/process-and-task-scheduling-labs/</link>
    <description>Process and Task Scheduling Labs Lab: ps ps ps Check manual pages: man ps Run with “every” and “full format” flags: ps -ef Produce an output with the command name in column 1, PID in column 2, PPID in column 3, and owner name in column 4, run it as follows: ps -o comm,pid,ppid,user Check how many sshd processes are currently running on the system: ps -C sshd Lab: top top top View manual page: man top Lab: List a specific process list the PID of the rsyslogd daemon pidof rsyslogd or pgrep rsyslogd Lab: Listing Processes by User and Group Ownership List processes owned by user1: ps -U user1 List processes owned by group root: ps -G root Lab: nice View the default nice value: nice List priority and niceness for all processes: ps -efl Lab: Start Processes at Non-Default Priorities (2 terminals) Run the top command at the default priority/niceness in Terminal 1: top Check the priority and niceness for the top command in Terminal 2 using the ps command: ps -efl | grep top Terminate the top session in Terminal 1 by pressing the letter q and relaunch it at a lower priority with a nice value of +2: nice -n 2 top \Check the priority and niceness for the top command in Terminal 2 using the ps command: ps -efl | grep top Terminate the top session in Terminal 1 by pressing the letter q and relaunch it at a higher priority with a nice value of -10. Use sudo for root privileges. sudo nice -n -10 top Check the priority and niceness for the top command in Terminal 2 using the ps command: ps -efl | grep top Terminate the top session by pressing the letter q. Lab: Alter Process Priorities (2 terminals) Run the top command at the default priority/niceness in Terminal 1: top Check the priority and niceness for the top command in Terminal 2 using the ps command: ps -efl | grep top While the top session is running in Terminal 1, increase its priority by renicing it to -5. Use the command substitution to get the PID of top. Prepend the renice command by sudo. The output indicates the old (0) and new (-5) priorities for the process. sudo renice -n -5 $(pidof top) Validate the above change with ps. Focus on columns 7 and 8. ps -efl | grep top Repeat the above but set the process to run at a lower priority by renicing it to 8: The output indicates the old (-5) and new (8) priorities for the process. sudo renice -n 8 $(pidof top) Validate the above change with ps. Focus on columns 7 and 8. ps -efl | grep top Lab: Controlling Processes with Signals Pass the soft termination signal to the crond daemon, use either of the following: sudo pkill crond # or sudo kill $(pidof crond) Confirm: ps -ef | grep crond Forcefully kill crond: sudo pkill -9 crond # or sudo pkill -s SIGKILL crond # or sudo kill -9 $(pgrep crond) Kill all crond processes: sudo killall crond View manual pages: man kill man pkill man killall Lab: cron and atd View log files for cron and atd sudo cat /var/log/cron Lab: at and crond run /home/user1/.bash_profile file for user1 2 hours from now: at -f ~/.bash_profile now + 2 hours Consult crontab manual pages: man crontab Lab: Submit, View, List, and Erase an at Job 1.Run the at command and specify the correct execution time and date for the job. Type the entire command at the first at&gt; prompt and press Enter. Press Ctrl+d at the second at&gt; prompt to complete the job submission and return to the shell prompt.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/linux/process-and-task-scheduling-labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>