<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://linuxreader.com/networking/ccna/newccnanotes/part3/</link>
    <description>1.0 Network Fundamentals&#xA;1.10 Identify IP parameters for Client OS (Windows, Mac OS, Linux)&#xA;4.0 IP Services&#xA;4.3 Explain the role of DHCP and DNS within the network&#xA;4.6 Configure and verify DHCP client and relay&#xA;DHCP Concepts&#xA;Four messages between the client and server (DORA): Discover: - Sent by the DHCP client to find a willing DHCP server Offer: - Sent by a DHCP server to offer to lease&#xA;Request: - Sent by the DHCP client to ask the server to lease the IPv4 address listed in the Offer message&#xA;Acknowledgment: - Sent by the DHCP server to assign the address and to list the mask, default router, and DNS server IP addresses IPv4 addresses that allow a host that has no IP address to still be able to send and receive messages on the local subnet: 0.0.0.0: - An address reserved for use as a source IPv4 address for hosts that do not yet have an IP address. 255.255.255.255: - The local broadcast IP address. Packets sent to this destination address are broadcast on the local data link, but routers do not forward them. a client, sends a Discover message, with source IP address of 0.0.0.0Host A sends the packet to destination 255.255.255.255 router R1 will not forward this packet. - - assuming the DHCP client chooses to use a DHCP option called the broadcast flag; all examples in this book assume the broadcast flag is used. - all hosts in the subnet receive the Offer message - the original Discover message lists a number called the client ID□□ includes the host’s MAC address, that identifies the original host (host A in this case).As a result, host A knows that the Offer message is meant for host A, which. Supporting DHCP for Remote Subnets with DHCP Relay</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://linuxreader.com/networking/ccna/newccnanotes/part3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>