<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux Reader</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>I’m David, I spin poi, read books, tinker, and write. Check out what I am doing Now!&#xA;I started keeping summaries, notes, and reviews of books that I am reading.&#xA;Let’s Chat! I reply to every email.&#xA;Here are the current areas of content you can find here:&#xA;Linux Stuff&#xA;Tools&#xA;Networking&#xA;Writing&#xA;&lt;— You can also click the links in the side bar.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:20:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:20:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/linux/</guid>
      <description>Fedora My Fedora Setup Silverblue RHCSA RHCSA Exam Environment Guide RHCSA Notes RHCSA Study Tracker RHCSA Vagrant Lab Setup You Need to Learn Man Pages RHCSA Stuff RHCSA Notes RHCSA Study Tracker Redhat Exam Environment How to Study for RHCSA RHCSA Study Points RHCSA Vagrant Lab Setup Fedora My Fedora Setup Silverblue Misc Using Man Pages wsl2 Bare Metal to Proxmox VM Labs Turn a file into a block device</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/networking/</guid>
      <description>CCNA Cisco to Juniper Cheat Sheet How to Study for the CCNA Exam My CCNA Notes Resources for Passing CCNA What to Learn After CCNA Juniper consoling_in_to_mx80_from_linux Juniper CLI Basics Junos Fundementals Paste Config on a Juniper Switch Toggle PoE on a Juniper Switch The formatting and images of all of my networking notes go destroyed when migrating away from OneNote. But they still come in handy all of the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/</guid>
      <description>Posts Vim Vim Guide Calibre Web with Docker and NGINX How to Build a website With Hugo How to Process Bookfusion Highlights with Vim How to Set Up Hugo Relearn Theme Nextcloud on RHEL Based Systems Self hosting a Nextcloud Server Using Vagrant on Linux</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>