<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux Reader</title>
    <link>http://linuxreader.com/</link>
    <description>I’m David, I spin poi, read books, tinker, and write. Check out what I am doing Now!&#xA;I started keeping summaries, notes, and reviews of books that I am reading.&#xA;Let’s Chat! I reply to every email.&#xA;Here are the current areas of content you can find here:&#xA;Linux Stuff&#xA;Tools&#xA;Networking&#xA;Writing&#xA;&lt;— You can also click the links in the side bar.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://linuxreader.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bash Scripting</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/bash-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/bash-scripting/</guid>
      <description>Shell ScriptingShell scripting and logical constructs</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containers</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/containers/</guid>
      <description>ContainersPodman Podman Podman</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Security</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/cyber-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/cyber-security/</guid>
      <description>Security Enhanced LinuxThe confusing world of SELinux&#xA;The Linux FirewallFirewalld stuff mostly</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>desktop</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/desktop/</guid>
      <description>My Fedora SetupMy Fedora Setup&#xA;SilverblueFedora Silverblue</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Learning Touch TypingLearning touch typing&#xA;Vim GuideGuide to using Vim</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/networking/</guid>
      <description>Cisco to Juniper Cheat SheetJuniper command equivalent to Cisco commands&#xA;consoling_in_to_mx80_from_linuxHow to console into an MX80 router from linux&#xA;DNS and Time SynchronizationDNS and Time Synchronization&#xA;How to Study for the CCNA Exam It took me a whopping 2 years to finish my CCNA! I kept giving up and quitting my studies for months at a time. Why? Because I couldn’t remember the massive amount of content covered in the CCNA. It felt hopeless. I could have done it in 6 month (or faster) if I knew how to study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RedHat</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/redhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/redhat/</guid>
      <description>redhat</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Storage</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/storage/</guid>
      <description>Nextcloud on RHEL Based SystemsI’m going to show you how to set up your own, self-hosted Nextcloud server using Alma Linux 9 and Apache.&#xA;What is Nextcloud? Nextcloud is so many things. It offers so many features and options, it deserves a bulleted list:&#xA;Free and open source Cloud storage and syncing Email client Custom browser dashboard with widgets Office suite RSS newsfeed Project organization (deck) Notebook Calender Task manager Connect to decentralized social media (like Mastodon) Replacement for all of google’s services Create web forms or surveys It is also free and open source. This mean the source code is available to all. And hosting yourself means you can guarantee that your data isn’t being shared.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/tools/</guid>
      <description>Posts Calibre Web with Docker and NGINXI couldn’t find a guide on how to set up Calibre web step-by-step as a Docker container. Especially not one that used Nginx as a reverse proxy.&#xA;The good news is that it is really fast and simple. You’ll need a few tools to get this done:&#xA;A server with a public IP address A DNS Provider (I use CloudFlare) Docker Nginx A Calibre Library Certbot Rsync First, sync your local Calibre library to a folder on your server:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization</title>
      <link>http://linuxreader.com/virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://linuxreader.com/virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Using Vagrant on LinuxHow to use Vagrant from a Linux computer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>