<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/booknotes/i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich/</link>
    <description>Set up accounts at solid banks. Automate day-to-day money management (bills, savings, debt payoff, etc.). Learn a bit about investing. Let your money grow for thirty years. “The single most important thing you can do to be rich is to start early.”&#xA;10 Rules for a Rich Life Spend on the things you love and cut costs mercilessly on the things you don’t. Focus on Big Wins, Like automating savings and investing, finding a job you love, and negotiating your salary. Investing should be very boring—and very profitable—over the long term. There’s a limit to how much you can cut, but no limit to how much you can earn. Politely listen to unwanted advice. But stick to your plan. Build a collection of “spending frameworks” to use when deciding on buying something Beware of the endless search for “advanced” tips. Focus on improving step by step. Do the basics, consistently. You’re in control. Nobody’s coming to rescue you. Once money isn’t a primary constraint, you’ll have the freedom to design your own Rich Life, which will almost certainly be different from the average person’s. Embrace it. This is the fun part! Live life outside the spreadsheet. Once you automate your money using the system in this book, you’ll see that the most important part of a Rich Life is outside the spreadsheet—it involves relationships, new experiences, and giving back. Credit Cards If you pay your bill on time, they’re a free short-term loan. Can help you keep track of your spending much more easily than cash, and they let you download your transaction history for free. Most offer free warranty extensions on your purchases and free rental car insurance. Many offer rewards and points worth hundreds or even thousands of dollars. As long as you manage them well, they’re worth having. Our largest purchases are almost always made on credit, and people with good credit save tens of thousands of dollars on these purchases. Two main components to your credit (also known as your credit history): your credit report and your credit score. credit report</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/booknotes/i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>